<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Strategy x Design</title>
    <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Strategy x Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 13:20:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/post/homepage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:35:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/post/homepage/</guid>
      <description>About me Hello, curious traveller to this bio. I am Tom Eldridge, a design strategist helping to build businesses, product and services that are sustainable and people orientated. ​​
What is strategic design and where do I fit in? ​​ I help organisations find the right opportunities to future-proof their business by helping them better integrate with the people and environments they operate in. Strategic Design builds on my background in service design, user research to create a more considered approach to services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>012 - Endings</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/012/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 13:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/012/</guid>
      <description>On Endings This is Hyper-normalisation, a monthly newsletter by Tom Eldridge on Strategic Design and this is the final edition. My intent with this newsletter was to keep it limited to 12 editions. These will now be archived on my website and the mailing list deleted. The internet/metaverse has given us many good things. But it’s very bad at endings and there is nothing sadder than seeing something limp on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>011 - Lightness &gt; Speed</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/011/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 12:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/011/</guid>
      <description>Refresh, Remake, and reverse Hello hypernormaliser reader
I&amp;rsquo;m writing this edition with storm Arwen roiling away in the background. As the studio is surrounded by woodland, it has the effect of sounding like the rolling waves crashing onto the beach.
 I built a new website. Over the years years I’ve been building websites to showcase my work. Squarespace was my go to web builder because it was simple to knock something fairly decent without any coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>010 - Acceleration</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/010/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Sep 2021 13:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/010/</guid>
      <description>Change, habits, and routine Hello hypernormaliser reader
In case you forgot, you subscribed to hypernormalisation a newsletter on strategic design by me, Tom Eldridge.
The autumn season feels more concrete now with reds and yellow leaf coverage popping out. If I was to summarise this past month for me it would be about change! Two cases of covid in my household threw my writing schedule out of kilter with some red-eye inducing early starts and long hours commuting by car.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>009 - A Smart City is an Unfinished City</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/009/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Sep 2021 13:24:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/009/</guid>
      <description>On Brian Eno&amp;rsquo;s Design Principles for city living Hello Reader
I realised that this newsletter can be hard to pin down. It zigs from cities, low carbon transportation, to systems, and to nature as a means of inspiration. Trying to wrangle these big themes into some sort of meaningful shape is tough. Tough in the sense that I&amp;rsquo;m constantly asking whether these topics hang together in a meaningful and engaging way?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>008 - Mobility: From Faster to Closer</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/008/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 10:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/008/</guid>
      <description>Designing services that are lighter and closer together Image: Adreas Levers - FlickR (Creative Commons) Hello Reader
This is a lighter edition than usual, due mainly to having taken some time off with my family this month. My first overseas trip in over 2 years and despite the extra safety steps it passed without incident. As soon as the aeroplane doors were pushed open, the warmth of the Spanish sun melted the past 18 months.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>007 - Systems of Cultivation</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/007/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jul 2021 10:04:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/007/</guid>
      <description>Systems for writing, systems for building, systems for culture Hello Normaliser,
After weeks of endless rain, I am writing this month&amp;rsquo;s newsletter in the sun. As a reminder as we spin into the second half of 2021, this newsletter will end in December.
Behind the Hypernormal curtain, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a Rube Goldberg construction with each post hand-coded in Hugo. The writing system is involved, with each new post sent as a Buttondown newsletter and a version for archive on my website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>006 - Designing for the climate crisis</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/006/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 13:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/006/</guid>
      <description>Nature-based solutions; a new operating system for building urban resiliance to climate change Salut Normaliser,
How the heck have we crested into the second half of the year? Over lockdown, I’ve had some days that feel compressed, and other days that seem endless. I’m starting to think that my mind misses the change of scenery when commuting to the office. But then I remember I save 3 hours daily by not commuting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>005 Prototyping Places</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/005/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 May 2021 08:38:37 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/005/</guid>
      <description>Sky bridges to nowhere; why we need more subcultural infrastructures; and new operating systems for placemaking Hello Normalisers
A bee hive update. Since last month there has been little progress on my hive being inhabited. The previous owners left an operating manual and from what is written down, the hive seems to be in the right spot - sunny with a clear flight path for the bees. Sadly, the window for colonizing the space is closing with many bees having found alternative accommodation before the summer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>004 The Long Bow</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/004/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 12:15:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/004/</guid>
      <description>Intro Greetings Readers
Green shoots and blossom are bloomin&#39; like crazy in my neck of the woods. It was a week before Christmas that my family and I moved into the new home. The trees were denuded and the garden was a mud bath. This month it is a welcome relief to see the garden start to come to life. As the days have got longer and warmer I stumbled on an item the previous owners had left behind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>003 Light Patterns Emerge From The Shadows</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/003/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 13:20:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/003/</guid>
      <description>Creating new futures from chaos - lessons from Fukushima; the rise of small distributed platforms; and is designing for the individual part of the problem? Intro Hyper-Normalisers!
Hello, its me Tom
Spring is in the air and whisper it there is a feeling of hope that things are changing for the better.
I wonder how we will look back at the great pause 2020/21? One of the niggling thoughts I have had since the start of the year is whether things will be genuinely different or will we snap back to how things were?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>002 The Future Mundane</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/002/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 20:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/002/</guid>
      <description>Designing for a future that&amp;rsquo;s a bit broken; what can we learn from indigenous technology; and the ambient sound of the future Intro Hello, subscribers to HyperNormalisation. A monthly newsletter that&amp;rsquo;s crypticaly about design and its capacity to create change. Your newsletter-er guide Tom here!
This 2nd edition has been fuelled by strong coffee and thin winter sun. February was all about snow in the UK. We had a big dollop of the good stuff that took me back to being a kid.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>001 Hammer &amp; Nail</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/001/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 20:12:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/hypernormal/001/</guid>
      <description>Google really wants to build a city of the future; why 80&amp;rsquo;s pop group Aha were strategic designers; and the challenge of a solution looking for a problem Hello reader. Yes, you! Slushy and cold footed Tom here!
This 1st edition is brought to you on a wet and cold lockdown January day. The light dusting of snow this morning has turned to a cold mizzle. This is 1 of 12 issues I’ve promised to publish in 2021 on a rag-tag range of topics that are loosely connected to the idea of design making space to change things.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Strategic Design?</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/about/what-is-strategic-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:51:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/about/what-is-strategic-design/</guid>
      <description>It’s hard to pin down a clear description of Strategic Design. It borrows from various splinters of design — interactive, systems, user, and urban to name a few. But why has it come about and why is it becoming increasingly popular? Strategic Design is partly a response to the challenges of modern life that has given rise to knotty problems so vast and complex a new way of thinking is needed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Do</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/about/what-i-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 18:51:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/about/what-i-do/</guid>
      <description>The services and experience I bring as a Design Strategist I can work as an independent consultant placed into your existing team or I can use my network of experiences researchers, Designers, and Product Managers to help you tackle a business design challenge. ​
Strategic Design Services   Value proposition development - I have experience with designing business models that fit a product or service to the needs of the audience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kickstart - Career building service for young people</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/kickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 18:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/kickstart/</guid>
      <description>Preventing long-term CV scarring for young people Young people in the UK were identified as being at risk from long-term CV scarring in 2020. A consequence of Covid-19 impacting the the UK economy.
The challenge was to design a Government backed service that gives young people the opportunity to gain work experience and skills. At the heart of the Kickstart scheme was a marketplace that matched employers to young people together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSI - Creating a service for international standards</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/bsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 18:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/bsi/</guid>
      <description>Remodelling Standards to help a new audience Over time the BSI had lost its way in understanding who its customers were and how BSI&amp;rsquo;s services could best meet their needs. If it continued down that path, BSI as a viable business would slide into irrelevance.
The problem space was how do you demonstrate the value of Standards to new and existing customers? Key to unlocking this, was understanding the service needed to reverse customer attrition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barclays Bank - Creating a smart financial coach service</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/barclaysbank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 18:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/barclaysbank/</guid>
      <description>Creating a smart financial coach service Barclays Retail Bank has managed to keep pace with challenger banks such as Monzo and Starling by rolling out a number of digital services. However the challenge for Barclays was how to better integrate these digital services with their existing branch and telephone touch-points so that customers get a joined up experience.
With the senior leadership team at Barclays Retail Bank I helped to design a unifying service for their products and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three - Reframing a flexible mobile tariff</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 18:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/three/</guid>
      <description>Reframing the mobile tariff that flexes In the face of a lack of differentiation across mobile network providers, Three was facing the dilemma of knowing it needed to change its consumer offering, while protecting its existing revenue.
My role as the strategic design lead was to explore how the business could pivot away from relying on revenue from contract and PAYG tariffs. To unpick this, the team and I worked with stakeholders to generate new opportunities that could work with their existing capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virgin Atlantic - Re-imagining the airport lounge of the future</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/virgin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 18:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/virgin/</guid>
      <description>Re-imagining the airport lounge of the future In response to the romance of air travel being slowly drained, Virgin were determined to create a compelling air lounge service experience for travellers.
My role was to create a service layer that challenged the accepted convention of sterile, impersonal airport lounges and to bring the glamour back to travel.
​A future state service was created through a number of stakeholder workshops and customer interviews I facilitated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natwest - Helping students achieve their financial goals</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/natwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 18:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/natwest/</guid>
      <description>A service design project to encourage students to save more frequently and to see their progress in meeting their saving goals Working with end users I looked to understand the deeper motivations for saving and their attitude to personal finance in general. From these user research sessions a series of concepts were created around different types of savers
These concepts were stress tested with NatWest stakeholders and with Students through Card Sorting and usability sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yunojuno - Redesigning the hiring process</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/yunojuno/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 18:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/yunojuno/</guid>
      <description>Redesigning the hiring process Changes by the UK Government on the hiring process of freelancers was going to have a big impact on YunoJuno’s business. Working with the YunoJuno board I redesigned their business proposition
YunoJuno is one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading marketplace for creative and tech freelancers. Changes by the UK Government on the hiring process of freelancers was going to have a big impact on YunoJuno’s business going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft &amp; SAP - Bringing cloud computing to life through art</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/microsoftsap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 18:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/microsoftsap/</guid>
      <description>An experimental project for Microsoft and SAP to bring the usually dry topic of cloud computing to life. Working with a number of well known design agencies and artists, a pop up art gallery was created on London&amp;rsquo;s South Bank.
Each art installation had a compelling story on cloud computing and the role it plays in our lives.
My role involved extensive stakeholder research with stakeholders and customoers to identfiy how something as abstract as cloud computing could be made real.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barclays Mortgages - Re-imagining the mortgage application experience</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/barclaysmortgages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 18:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/barclaysmortgages/</guid>
      <description>Arranging a mortgage can be a slow, difficult, and emotionally draining. One of the UK’s largest mortgage providers realised this and wanted to rethink how it could be done better.
Working with senior stakeholders and customers, I mapped out the existing mortgage journey – capturing the business processes, regulation requirements, and the customers&#39; thoughts and feelings at every step. From this service map I worked with a team of designers and stakeholders in the business to identify painpoints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vodafone - Designing an urban mobility tracking service</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/vodafone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 18:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/vodafone/</guid>
      <description>Designing an urban mobility tracking service A service design project with Vodafone Innovation team to explore and develop a service aimed at urban bike &amp;amp; moped commuters to track their vehicles from their mobile, giving them greater sense of security
A service design project with Vodafone Innovation team to explore and develop a service aimed at urban bike, &amp;amp; moped commuters to track their vehicles from their smart phone, giving them greater sense of security.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
