<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio on Strategy x Design</title>
    <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Portfolio on Strategy x Design</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2020 19:29:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kickstart - Career building service for young people</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/kickstart/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 18:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/kickstart/</guid>
      <description>Preventing long-term CV scarring for young people Young people in the UK were identified as being at risk from long-term CV scarring in 2020. A consequence of Covid-19 impacting the the UK economy.
The challenge was to design a Government backed service that gives young people the opportunity to gain work experience and skills. At the heart of the Kickstart scheme was a marketplace that matched employers to young people together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BSI - Creating a service for international standards</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/bsi/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 18:55:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/bsi/</guid>
      <description>Remodelling Standards to help a new audience Over time the BSI had lost its way in understanding who its customers were and how BSI&amp;rsquo;s services could best meet their needs. If it continued down that path, BSI as a viable business would slide into irrelevance.
The problem space was how do you demonstrate the value of Standards to new and existing customers? Key to unlocking this, was understanding the service needed to reverse customer attrition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barclays Bank - Creating a smart financial coach service</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/barclaysbank/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2019 18:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/barclaysbank/</guid>
      <description>Creating a smart financial coach service Barclays Retail Bank has managed to keep pace with challenger banks such as Monzo and Starling by rolling out a number of digital services. However the challenge for Barclays was how to better integrate these digital services with their existing branch and telephone touch-points so that customers get a joined up experience.
With the senior leadership team at Barclays Retail Bank I helped to design a unifying service for their products and services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Three - Reframing a flexible mobile tariff</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/three/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2019 18:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/three/</guid>
      <description>Reframing the mobile tariff that flexes In the face of a lack of differentiation across mobile network providers, Three was facing the dilemma of knowing it needed to change its consumer offering, while protecting its existing revenue.
My role as the strategic design lead was to explore how the business could pivot away from relying on revenue from contract and PAYG tariffs. To unpick this, the team and I worked with stakeholders to generate new opportunities that could work with their existing capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virgin Atlantic - Re-imagining the airport lounge of the future</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/virgin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2019 18:54:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/virgin/</guid>
      <description>Re-imagining the airport lounge of the future In response to the romance of air travel being slowly drained, Virgin were determined to create a compelling air lounge service experience for travellers.
My role was to create a service layer that challenged the accepted convention of sterile, impersonal airport lounges and to bring the glamour back to travel.
​A future state service was created through a number of stakeholder workshops and customer interviews I facilitated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natwest - Helping students achieve their financial goals</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/natwest/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2019 18:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/natwest/</guid>
      <description>A service design project to encourage students to save more frequently and to see their progress in meeting their saving goals Working with end users I looked to understand the deeper motivations for saving and their attitude to personal finance in general. From these user research sessions a series of concepts were created around different types of savers
These concepts were stress tested with NatWest stakeholders and with Students through Card Sorting and usability sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yunojuno - Redesigning the hiring process</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/yunojuno/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Nov 2018 18:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/yunojuno/</guid>
      <description>Redesigning the hiring process Changes by the UK Government on the hiring process of freelancers was going to have a big impact on YunoJuno’s business. Working with the YunoJuno board I redesigned their business proposition
YunoJuno is one of the UK&amp;rsquo;s leading marketplace for creative and tech freelancers. Changes by the UK Government on the hiring process of freelancers was going to have a big impact on YunoJuno’s business going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Microsoft &amp; SAP - Bringing cloud computing to life through art</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/microsoftsap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2017 18:55:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/microsoftsap/</guid>
      <description>An experimental project for Microsoft and SAP to bring the usually dry topic of cloud computing to life. Working with a number of well known design agencies and artists, a pop up art gallery was created on London&amp;rsquo;s South Bank.
Each art installation had a compelling story on cloud computing and the role it plays in our lives.
My role involved extensive stakeholder research with stakeholders and customoers to identfiy how something as abstract as cloud computing could be made real.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barclays Mortgages - Re-imagining the mortgage application experience</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/barclaysmortgages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Apr 2016 18:56:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/barclaysmortgages/</guid>
      <description>Arranging a mortgage can be a slow, difficult, and emotionally draining. One of the UK’s largest mortgage providers realised this and wanted to rethink how it could be done better.
Working with senior stakeholders and customers, I mapped out the existing mortgage journey – capturing the business processes, regulation requirements, and the customers&#39; thoughts and feelings at every step. From this service map I worked with a team of designers and stakeholders in the business to identify painpoints.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vodafone - Designing an urban mobility tracking service</title>
      <link>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/vodafone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Sep 2015 18:55:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.strategyxdesign.co.uk/portfolio/vodafone/</guid>
      <description>Designing an urban mobility tracking service A service design project with Vodafone Innovation team to explore and develop a service aimed at urban bike &amp;amp; moped commuters to track their vehicles from their mobile, giving them greater sense of security
A service design project with Vodafone Innovation team to explore and develop a service aimed at urban bike, &amp;amp; moped commuters to track their vehicles from their smart phone, giving them greater sense of security.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
